6316 Pepperell St., Halifax NS, B3H 2P3

Professional Profile

Radiation Therapist with over 7 years experience in providing patient centred care in radiation oncology. A practice leader in the department, that consistently innovates and implements new ideas. Passion for driving incremental and transformational change. Strategically minded to achieve long-term goals, but able to pivot to take advantage situations as they arise for high impact solutions. Aspiring to transition into a more formal management, and leadership position.

Relevant Experience

Jul. 2016 - Present Radiation Therapist Nova Scotia Cancer Centre (Halifax)

- Leading transformational change as part of the project team assigned to the first Ethos treatment unit with Hypersight in the world, which introduces paradigm-shifting advancements in treatment delivery.
- As a clinical leader, identified and engaged a shortlist of interested stakeholders within the department in preparation for striking a clinical working group for the Ethos project.
- Provided critical coverage as secondary on-site EMR system admin to ensure support is provided to patient care leaders and clinical teams, by responding to urgent issues.
- Developed efficient workflows that reflect clinical practice using knowledge of current clinical systems (Corepoint, STAR, ARIA, MediTech, OneContent) and IT best practices.
- Presented strategic advice to clinical leaders of the Radiation oncology department on the best way to leverage tools in the ARIA EMR system, Most recently advised on ways to reduce referral office workload and empower residents to identify patients that are candidates for their clinic that will be implemented in late March.
- Leveraging tools available in the EMR System to design a process to track disruptions in workflow in order to identify upstream issues and hidden work that is often not logged.
- Currently leading a practice group to investigate the implementing a change in practice for prostate treatments that will overturn a central tenet of radiation therapy.
- Lead therapist on Gynaecological, Lower GI, Full Body, Rapid Response and Overflow unit during the height of the pandemic. (Feb 2020 Aug 2021)
- Led unit through a difficult and complex time by demonstrating strategic thinking, effective communication and decision-making skills to adapt to rapidly changing circumstances day to day.
- Mentored and orientated new staff to the unit by providing a refresher on all relevant treatment procedures and ensuring staff has access to the updated protocols.
- Collaborated with multidisciplinary Breast, GI, Gynaecological, Palliative, and Whole Body Irradiation oncology working groups to identify and implement strategic process improvements for treatment delivery, with a focus on therapist autonomy and unit efficiency. Examples include early adoption, implementation and promotion of new technologies by highlighting relevant benefits in accordance to adult learning principles.
- Maintained currency on a broad portfolio of treatment techniques.
- Liaised frequently with management and charges to ensure scheduling of appropriate resources were in place and that the team was up to date on the latest policies.

Jan. 2023 - Present
Nov. 2020 - Present
Member,

Vice-Chair, Nova Scotia College of Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Professionals

Member,

- Achieved a strong understanding of the regulatory landscape in Nova Scotia and current legislative agendas
- Developed a strong understanding of the framework governing the professions regulated by the NSCMIRTP
- Oversaw the Finance committee as chair, assisting in the preparation of budgets and scrutinizing financial reports since Jan 2021.

Jun. 2013 - July 2015 Director, Toronto Ultimate Club Board

- Familiarized myself with the nuance of employment law by interpreting advice provided by consultants and subject matter experts.
- Accomplished a successful transition from a contractor employment model into an employee model

• Vetted and interviewed candidates for the Executive Director position at TUC

Apr. 2011 - May 2012 **Regent, Victoria University Board of Regents**

- Advocated for the reinvestment of surplus funds into visible student projects and special project funding to improve the student experience
- Represented the student persecutive in the development of a new student centre. Obtained support for
 architectural changes to benefit students such as improved accessibility, connectivity and access to charging
 infrastructure for technological devices such as laptops, tablets etc.

Dec 2010 - Jan 2012 Manager, Cat's Eye Pub and Student Event Space

- Trained and supervised 33 volunteer members on the Cat's Eve Subcommittee
- Oversaw the redesign and renovations to be made to the space as part of the development of a new student centre
- Supervised the demolition, storage of equipment and reestablishment of the Cat's Eye in a temporary space during the renovation period
- Maintained and established relationships with key personnel at the University to ensure a seamless transition in the present and future.
- Developed and oversaw an annual budget of \$12,000 with strategic investments to provide additional resources for future managers when the renovated space would reopen

Mar 2010 - Nov 2010 **Orientation Executive,** Victoria University

- Designed, implemented and oversaw a week long schedule of programming for ~1000 incoming first time university students
- Trained, organized, scheduled and directed a team of over 100 volunteers to ensure a safe environment for new students on move in day and during the week.
- Identified trusted leaders to complete demanding assignments independently or with some support.
- Supported the development and allocation of an operational budget in excess of \$100,000 in a transparent and equitable fashion.
- Organized a novel system of managing and accessing photos for orientation week with recommendations for future implementations and long-term storage.

Education

Jun. 2016 - Present	Certified MRT(T) (87775), Canadian Association of Medical Radiation Technologists
Jun. 2016 - Present	Certified MRT(T) (10710), Nova Scotia College of Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Professionals
Jan. 2020 - Present	Advanced Certificate, Magnetic Resonance Imaging, British Columbia Institute of Technology
Sept. 2013 - Jun. 2016	Bachelors of Science, Medical Radiation Sciences, University of Toronto
Sept. 2007 - Jun. 2012	Bachelors of Science, Biochemistry Specialist, University of Toronto

References

Available upon request